
{
  "translations": {
    "en": {
      "q2":{
        "type": "select",
        "description": "$\\textbf {Derivation Trees}$ (also known as 'parse trees'): A derivation tree represents a derivation, but does not show the order in which productions were applied.",
        "question": "How many ways that we can use to represent string derivations from grammars?",
        "answer": ["Derivation trees","sentential forms"],
        "choices": ["Derivation trees","sentential forms"]
      },
      "q3":{
        "type": "true/false",
        "description": "A derivation tree for $G=(V,T,S,P)$ is built by setting the root node label to be $S$",
        "question": "The reason for that is we always start deriving a string from the grammar start variable",
        "answer": "True",
        "choices": []
      },
      "q4":{
        "type": "true/false",
        "description": "A derivation tree for $G=(V,T,S,P)$ is built by setting the root node label to be $S$<br/>The clidren of a node will be the RHS of the production rule that we need to use to derive the string.",
        "question": "The children for any node can be variables and/or terminals",
        "answer": "True",
        "choices": []
      },
      "q5":{
        "type": "true/false",
        "description": "A derivation tree for $G=(V,T,S,P)$ is built by setting the root node label to be $S$<br/>The clidren of a node will be the RHS of the production rule that we need to use to derive the string.<br>leaves are labeled $x$, where $x\\in T\\cup \\{\\lambda \\}$",
        "question": "The leaves nodes can be variables and/or terminals",
        "answer": "False",
        "choices": []
      },
      "q6":{
        "type": "true/false",
        "description": "A derivation tree for $G=(V,T,S,P)$ is built by setting the root node label to be $S$<br/>The clidren of a node will be the RHS of the production rule that we need to use to derive the string.<br>leaves are labeled $x$, where $x\\in T\\cup \\{\\lambda \\}$<br>Nonleaf vertices labeled $A$, where $A\\in V$",
        "question": "The non-leaves nodes will be variables",
        "answer": "True",
        "choices": []
      },
      "q8":{
        "type": "select",
        "description": "$\\textbf{Definitions:}$ Partial derivation tree is a subtree of a derivation tree.",
        "question": "The tree on the left is",
        "answer": "partial derivation tree",
        "choices": ["derivation tree", "partial derivation tree"]
      },
      "q9":{
        "type": "select",
        "description": "$\\textbf{Definitions:}$ Partial derivation tree is a subtree of a derivation tree.<br/>If partial derivation tree has root $S$ then it represents a sentential form",
        "question": "What is the sentential form equivalent to the partial derivation tree on the left?",
        "answer": "$S\\rightarrow AcB \\quad A\\rightarrow aAa$",
        "choices": ["$S\\rightarrow AcB$", "$S\\rightarrow aAacB$", "$S\\rightarrow AcB \\quad A\\rightarrow aAa$"]
      },
      "q10":{
        "type": "select",
        "description": "$\\textbf{Definitions:}$ Partial derivation tree is a subtree of a derivation tree.<br/>If partial derivation tree has root $S$ then it represents a sentential form. Leaves from left to right in a derivation tree form the yield of the tree.",
        "question": "What is the yield for the partial derivation tree on the left?",
        "answer": "aAacB",
        "choices": ["aAacB", "AcBaAa", "cbaAa"]
      },
      "q11":{
        "type": "select",
        "description": "$\\textbf{Definitions:}$ Partial derivation tree is a subtree of a derivation tree.<br/>If partial derivation tree has root $S$ then it represents a sentential form. Leaves from left to right in a derivation tree form the yield of the tree.",
        "question": "The tree on the lef is ",
        "answer": "derivation tree",
        "choices": ["derivation tree", "partial derivation tree"]
      },
      "q12":{
        "type": "select",
        "description": "$\\textbf{Definitions:}$ Partial derivation tree is a subtree of a derivation tree.<br/>If partial derivation tree has root $S$ then it represents a sentential form. Leaves from left to right in a derivation tree form the yield of the tree.",
        "question": "What is the yield for the partial derivation tree on the left?",
        "answer": "aac",
        "choices": ["aac", "caa", "cbaa"]
      },
      "q13":{
        "type": "true/false",
        "description": "$\\textbf{Definitions:}$ Partial derivation tree is a subtree of a derivation tree.<br/>If partial derivation tree has root $S$ then it represents a sentential form. Leaves from left to right in a derivation tree form the yield of the tree.<br/>If $w$ is the yield of a derivation tree, then it must be that $w\\in L(G)$.",
        "question": "Since the string $aac$ is the yield of the tree, then $aac \\in L(G)$",
        "answer": "True",
        "choices": []
      },
      "q_7":{
        "type": "multiple",
        "description": "$G$ =($\\{S,A,B\\}$,$\\{a,b,c\\}$,S,P) <br>$S\\rightarrow AcB$<br> $A\\rightarrow aAa$ | $\\lambda$<br> $B\\rightarrow Bbb$ | $\\lambda$",
        "question": "What should $S \\rightarrow$ be if we want the same number of a's and b's?",
        "answer": "$c | aaSbb$",
        "choices": ["$aaSbb$", "$c | aaSbb$", "$c$", "$c | aaSb$", "$aaSb$"] 
      },
      "q_8":{
        "type": "multiple",
        "description": " $G=(\\{S\\},\\{a,b\\},S,P)$,P=<br> $S\\rightarrow SS$ | aSa | b | $\\lambda$<br> $L1=L(G)=\\{w\\in \\Sigma^âˆ—| strings \\ with \\ an \\ even \\ number \\ of \\ a's\\}$",
        "question": "Is $abbab \\in L(G)$",
        "answer": "Yes",
        "choices": ["Yes", "No"] 
      }
    }
  }
}
